Finding Aid for Henry B. Joy Historical Research Records ca. 1812-1937
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Henry B. Joy Historical Research Records circa 1812-1937
Henry B. Joy Historical Research (Organization)
The Henry B. Joy Historical Research (HBJHR) was an office established and funded by Detroit businessman Henry B. Joy in 1928 to do original research into the life and career of James F. Joy; the series in the collection are James F. Joy Papers, Railroad Enterprises, John W. Brooks Papers, Abraham Lincoln Research, and Office Correspondence.
851609, Bp/2, UBPm
27 linear feet
2 oversize volumes
2 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The records of this organization were the gift of Mrs. Henry B. Joy and came to the library in 1946. The record group was formerly cataloged as the papers of James F. Joy. Donor no. 2204
The record group is open for research.
The Henry B. Joy Historical Research (HBJHR) was an office established and funded by Detroit businessman Henry B. Joy in 1928 to do original research into the life and career of James F. Joy, Henry's father, who was a lawyer and railroad entrepreneur. The first director of the office was Stephen I. Gilchrist; M.C. McConkey was assistant director. Soon after beginning his study of James F. Joy, Gilchrist convinced Henry B. Joy to broaden the scope of HBJHR to include the life of Abraham Lincoln. While a Springfield attorney, Lincoln was employed by Joy on litigation arising out of the extension of the Michigan Central line into Chicago and the subsequent use needed of tracks belonging to the Illinois Central Railroad. Henry B. Joy was fascinated by Lincoln and wanted to produce a reliable life of the Civil War president.
Working out of a Detroit office building, Gilchrist and McConkey diligently sought out materials on Joy and Lincoln. Although they fully intended to publish the results of their research, they never did. Gilchrist produced a draft history of the Chicago Burlington and Quincy Railroad and a life of Abraham Lincoln, while McConkey authored a biography of Joy. All of these works remain unpublished. A few months after the death of Henry B. Joy in 1936, the office closed and the materials were given over to Mrs. Henry B. Joy.
The collection has been arranged in the same groupings of materials as received. The names given to these series groupings are James F. Joy Papers, Railroad Enterprises, John W. Brooks Papers, Abraham Lincoln Research, and Office Correspondence.
The materials accumulated by The Henry B. Joy Historical Research organization consist largely of copied documents from historical repositories. The vast bulk of the collection was taken from the James Joy papers on file at the Burton Historical Collection. The source of other copied material is not readily apparent but might have come from the archives of the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad which since 1943 has been at the Newberry Library in Chicago. The HBJHR must have had a considerable budget as the collection consists of many hundreds of photostatic copies (both positive and negative) as well as typescripts for many of the same materials.
Subjects:
Chicago, Burlington & Quincy Railroad Company.; Illinois Central Railroad Company.; Joy, James F. (James Frederick), 1810-1896.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Railroads--United States.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Joy, James F. (James Frederick), 1810-1896.
Contributors:
Brooks, John W.; Chandler, Zachariah, 1813-1879.; Fillmore, Millard, 1800-1874.; Joy, James F. (James Frederick), 1810-1896.; Ledyard, Henry, 1812-1880.; Story, Joseph, 1779-1845.
Genre/Form:
Prints.; Photographs.
- James F. Joy Papers
  The James F. Joy series is comprised of four major subseries: Photographs, Letters, Business Correspondence, and Joy Research. Photographs and Letters are small subseries, containing (except for the Office Correspondence series) the bulk of the original, non-copied, material within the collection. Included are portraits of Joy and a scattering of business and political letters from Millard Fillmore, Zachariah Chandler, Joseph W. Story, and Henry B. Ledyard.
  - Photographs
    - Portraits, etc. (Box 1)
      (also see oversize portraits and print in UBPm folders)
  - Letters
    - Letters from Millard Fillmore, Zachariah Chandler, Joseph W. Story, and Henry B. Ledyard, 1 folders (Box 1)
      (originals)
  - Business correspondence
    The Business Correspondence subseries is more substantial. This subseries is further divided into a chronological files and an alphabetical files. The Business Correspondence subseries, like much of the collection, consists of both negative and positive photostatic copies of documents and typescripts (either complete or partial) of these same documents.
    - By date
      - 1829-1864 (Box 1)
        (positive photostatic copies)
      - 1865-1868 (Box 2)
    - Alphabetical
      (negative photostatic copies)
      - Allen, Edward L. (Box 2)
      - Baker, Edward L. (Box 2)
      - Baker, J.H. (Box 2)
      - Baldwin, H.P. (Box 2)
      - Barnard, J.F. (Box 2)
      - Bartlett, Sidney (Box 2)
      - Bates, George C. (Box 2)
      - Blair, Austin (Box 2)
      - Blair, C.B. (Box 2)
      - Bradbury, C. (Box 2)
      - Brayman, Mason (Box 2)
      - Bronson, Frederic (Box 2)
      - Brooks, J.W. (Box 2)
      - Brown, S.G. (Box 2)
      - Browning, O.H. (Box 2)
      - Brydges, C.V. (Box 2)
      - Burch, I.H. (Box 2)
      - Burnham, J. Appleton (Box 2)
      - Burnham, John A. (Box 2)
      - Burrall, W.P. (Box 2)
      - Bushnell, Nehemiah (Box 2)
      - Carper, S. (Box 2)
      - Caton, I.D. (Box 2)
      - Chamberlain, E.M. (Box 2)
      - Chandler, Zachariah (Box 2)
      - Chanute, Octave (Box 2)
      - Chapin, Henry (Box 2)
      - Choate, Joseph H. (Box 2)
      - Christiancy, I.P. (Box 2)
      - Church, Ella (Box 2)
      - Clark, George J. (Box 2)
      - Clough, William McNeill (Box 2)
      - Coates, Kersey (Box 2)
      - Coolbaugh, William F. (Box 2)
      - Corning, Erastus (Box 2)
      - Craig, James (Box 2)
      - Crane, Joshua (Box 2)
      - Crapo, Henry H. (Box 2)
      - Crowell, I. (Box 2)
      - Cunningham, C.L. (Box 2)
      - Curtis, J. (Box 2)
      - Custard, R.R. (Box 2)
      - Davis, George M. (Box 2)
      - Denison, John N. (Box 2)
      - Dewey, George M. (Box 2)
      - Dexter, Wirt (Box 2)
        (also includes originals)
      - Douglass, John M. (Box 2)
      - Douglass, Stephen A. (Box 2)
      - Duffield, D.B. (Box 2)
      - Farnsworth, Elon (Box 2)
      - Felch, Alpheus (Box 2)
      - Forbes, J.M. (Box 2)
      - Gale, G.W. (Box 2)
      - Grant & Smith (Box 2)
      - Graves, J.K. (Box 2)
      - Green, John C. (Box 2)
      - Greenleaf, Simon (Box 2)
      - Grimes, J.W. (Box 2)
      - Griswold, George (Box 2)
      - Griswold, J.N.A. (Box 2)
      - Guiteau, J.M. (Box 2)
      - Hall, Amos T. (Box 2)
      - Hall, J.C. (Box 2)
      - Hammond, C.G. (Box 2)
      - Hannah, W.C. (Box 2)
      - Hill, S.H. (Box 2)
      - Hodgson, John (Box 2)
      - Holliday, C.K. (Box 2)
      - Howard, William A. (Box 2)
      - Hutchins, George H. (Box 2)
      - Ingraham, N. D. (Box 2)
      - Jaffray, Robert & Co. (Box 2)
      - Joy & Porter (firm) (Box 2)
      - Joy, Charles F. (Box 2)
      - Joy, Hannah (Box 2)
      - Joy, James F. (various), 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Joy, James, Jr. (Box 2)
      - Joy, James (father of JFJ) (Box 2)
      - Joy, John Pickering (Box 3)
      - Joy, Lyman F. (Box 3)
      - Joy, Martha (Box 3)
      - Joy, Mary B. (Box 3)
      - Joy, Richard P. (Box 3)
      - Joy, Sarah Reed (Box 3)
      - Joy, Sarah (Box 3)
      - Joy, Sylvester (Box 3)
      - Judd, N.B. (Box 3)
      - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 3)
      - Livingstone, Caroline (Box 3)
      - Lockwood, J.W. (Box 3)
      - Lothrop, G.V.N. (Box 3)
      - McClellan, R.H. (Box 3)
      - McDonell, D.L. (Box 3)
      - McDonell, John (Box 3)
      - McDowell, C.C. (Box 3)
      - Mason, R.B. (Box 3)
      - Merriam, Charles (Box 3)
      - Moore, E.S. (Box 3)
      - Moore, Franklin (Box 3)
      - Morrison, A.H. (Box 3)
      - Morton, J. Sterling (Box 3)
      - Movius, Julius (Box 3)
      - Murphy, W.W. (Box 3)
      - Neal, David A.Nettleton, George (Box 3)
      - Noyes & Tracy (Box 3)
      - Osborn, A.L. (Box 3)
      - Osborn, W.H. (Box 3)
      - Otto, W.T. (Box 3)
      - Peck, E. (Box 3)
      - Perkins, C.E. (Box 3)
      - Perry, John D. (Box 3)
      - Phillips, E.B. (Box 3)
      - Pierce, Charles W. (Box 3)
      - Pittman, J.E. (Box 3)
      - Pomeroy, R.M. (Box 3)
      - Porter, A.S. (Box 3)
      - Porter, George F. (Box 3)
      - Pruyn, John (Box 3)
      - Pullman, George M. (Box 3)
      - Quimby, E.T. (Box 3)
      - Read, John G. (Box 3)
      - Ross (Box 3)
      - Russell, Alfred (Box 3)
      - Russell, James A. (Box 3)
      - Sargent, H.E. (Box 3)
      - Savery, J.C. (Box 3)
      - Schuyler, George S. (Box 3)
      - Scoville, N.H. & Sons (Box 3)
      - Shumaker, R.M. (Box 3)
      - Silberschmidt, H.H. (Box 3)
      - Sindley, Charles P. (Box 3)
      - Sloan, Samuel (Box 3)
      - Smith, E.S. (Box 3)
      - Smith, Elijah (Box 3)
      - Stansbury, Edward A. (Box 3)
      - Sternbergh, J. (Box 3)
      - Stewart, Charles H. (Box 3)
      - Strong, H. (Box 3)
      - Sturges (Box 3)
      - Talman, G.F. (Box 3)
      - Taylor, Moses (Box 3)
      - Thayer, Nathaniel (Box 3)
      - Thompson, Benjamin (Box 3)
      - Trowbridge, Charles A. (Box 3)
      - Turner, F.G. (Box 3)
      - Van Nortwick, John (Box 3)
      - Vanderbilt, William H. (Box 3)
      - Walker, J.M. (Box 3)
      - Warner, William (Box 3)
      - Watson, R.S. (Box 3)
      - Wentworth, John (Box 3)
      - Wells, D.L. (Box 3)
      - Williams, J. (Box 3)
      - Williamson, D.D. (Box 3)
      - Wilson, James S. (Box 3)
      - Wyatt, F.O. (Box 3)
    - By date
      Typescripts of originals
      - 1849-1854 (Box 3)
      - 1855-1866 (Box 4)
      - 1867-1868 1874-1894 (Box 5)
  - Joy Research
    The Joy Research subseries includes collected materials about Joy, his family, and his various interests. There are five major divisions under Joy Research. The Joy Chronology consists of typescripts of letters and other documents largely from the Joy collection at the Burton Historical Collections. These materials were formerly placed into binders and arranged by date. The Joy By Date file is similar to the Chronology except that it also includes newspaper articles, typescripts and photostatic copies. What Gilchrist and McConkey termed Joy Biography are files consisting of Joy's writings and obituaries of Joy from various newspapers. The Joy Family file is arranged by name of family member. Composed in part of copied documents and research materials, this file is notable for a few original documents such as Timothy Joy's diary kept in 1812. The last file, labeled here as Biography, is the unpublished McConkey biography of James F. Joy.
    - Chronology
      (formerly in binders)
      - 1810-1851 (Box 5)
      - 1852-1896 (Box 6)
    - Joy by date
      - 1836-1896 (Box 7)
    - Joy biography
      - Filed material (Box 7)
        (include writings, obituaries, etc.)
    - Joy family
      - Joy family (various) (Box 7)
        (include diary of family member, 1838)
      - Bourne family (Box 7)
      - Joy, Charles F. (JFJ nephew) (Box 7)
      - Joy, Henry B. (JFJ's son) (Box 7)
      - Joy, James (father of JFJ) (Box 7)
        (James Joy, Sr. refers to JFJ as Frederick)
      - Joy, Richard P. (brother of JFJ) (Box 7)
      - Joy, Sarah (Box 7)
        (file contains a mixture of materials pertaining to JFJ's sister and his daughter both named Sarah)
      - Joy, Sylvester (brother of JFJ) (Box 7)
        (include original letter 1855 to JFJ regarding his debts)
      - Joy, Thomas (ancestor of JFJ, prominent colonial architect) (Box 7)
      - Joy, Timothy, 2 folders (Box 7)
        (include diary of Timothy Joy written from Ipswich Prison in Massachusetts, 1812)
    - Biography
      - M. C. McConkey biography of Joy, 5 volumes; 1 folders (Box 8)
- Railroad Enterprises
  The second series in the collection - Railroad Enterprises - is the material accumulated by the Joy research organization pertaining to James F. Joy's activities as a railroad entrepreneur. This series is composed of nine subseries relating to eight railroads or railroad groupings and one general topical file of research information. The railroad subseries include: Michigan Central Railroad, Illinois Central Railroad, Chicago, Burlington & Quincy Railroad, Burlington & Missouri River Railroad, Hannibal & St. Joseph Railroad, and Kansas City and Cameron Railroad. The two railroad groupings are for the subsidiaries of the Chicago, Burlington & Quincy Railroad and those railroad lines known as the River Roads. The River Roads included the Chicago Clinton & Dubuque, the Clinton and Dubuque, the Dubuque and Minnesota, the Chicago, Dubuque & Minnesota, and the Chicago, Clinton and Minnesota.
  - Michigan Central Railroad
    - 1837-1906 (Box 9)
  - Illinois Central Railroad
    - History (Box 9)
    - By date 1850-1852 (Box 9)
    - By date 1852-1876 (Box 10)
    - Documents relating to its founding (Box 11)
    - Published material (Box 11)
    - Main contract (Box 11)
    - Collected research materials, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad
    - History of Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad by Stephen Ira Gilchrist entitled, "'We Seven' of the 'Q'; a study in railways and character"(unprocessed) (3 expandable folders) (Box 11)
    - History of Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad by Stephen Ira Gilchrist entitled, "'We Seven' of the 'Q'; a study in railways and character"(unprocessed) (1 expandable folder) (Box 12)
    - Published material (Box 12)
    - By date 1852-1902 (Box 12)
    - Map (Box 12)
    - Lists of directors and officers (Box 12)
    - Brunswick, Duke of (Box 12)
    - Aurora Branch 1849-1852 (Box 12)
    - Chicago and Aurora 1849-1856 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Minutes of meetings 1854-1877, 2 volumes (Volume 1)
      (photostatic copies)
  - Burlington and Missouri River Railroad
    - By date 1835-1881 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Hannibal and St. Joseph Railroad
    - By date 1851-1890 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Kansas City and Cameron Railroad
    - By date 1857-1976 (Box 13)
      (scattered dates)
  - Q subsidiaries
    - American Central (Box 13)
    - Burlington and Northwestern Railroad (Box 13)
    - Burlington and Southwestern Railroad (Box 13)
    - Carthage & Burlington (Box 13)
    - Central Military Tract (Box 13)
    - Chicago & Iowa (Box 13)
    - Chicago & Rock River (Box 13)
    - Chicago, Burlington & Kansas City (Box 13)
    - Dixon, Peoria & Hannibal (Box 13)
    - Jacksonville & Savannah (Box 13)
    - Kansas City, Galveston & Lake Superior (Box 13)
    - Kansas City, St. Joseph & Council Bluffs (Box 13)
    - Keokuk & St. Paul (Box 13)
    - Missouri Valley (Box 13)
    - Northern Cross (Box 13)
    - Ottawa, Oswego & Fox River Valley (Box 13)
    - Peoria & Hannibal (Box 13)
    - Peoria & Oquawka (Box 13)
    - Quincy, Alton & St. Louis (Box 13)
    - Quincy & Chicago (Box 13)
    - Quincy & Palmyra (Box 13)
    - Quincy & Warsaw (Box 13)
    - St. Charles Air Line (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous various lines (Box 13)
  - River Roads
    - 1856-1874 (Box 13)
    - 1875-1877 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Topical file
    (pamphlets, copies of documents)
    The Topical Files subseries is arranged alphabetically and consists of typescripts (complete or excerpted) of letters and other documents, excerpts from books magazine and newspaper articles with information relevant to Joy and his career, and other collected background information.
    - Allan Sheldon & Co. (Box 14)
    - Atchison, Topeka & Sante Fe RR (Box 14)
    - Bank interests (Box 14)
    - Bates v. Illinois Central RR, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Blaine-Beecher dispute (Box 15)
    - Bowen and Howard manuscript (Box 15)
    - Bridges
      - Buffalo (Box 15)
      - Burlington (Box 15)
      - Clinton (Box 15)
      - Detroit drawbridge, etc., 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Kansas City, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Leavenworth (Box 15)
      - Quincy (Box 15)
    - Brunswick, Duke of (Box 15)
    - Buffalo and Mississippi RR (Box 15)
    - Burch case (Box 15)
    - Burlington and Missouri River RR (Box 15)
    - Chandler, Zachariah (Box 15)
    - Chicago & Alton RR (Box 15)
    - Chicago Board of Trade (Box 15)
    - Chicago, Burlington & Quincy RR (Box 15)
    - Chicago Land Company (Box 15)
    - Chicago Times case (Box 15)
    - Civil War topics (Box 15)
    - Costs per mile (Box 15)
    - Depots
      - Chicago (Box 15)
      - Detroit, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Kansas City (Box 15)
    - Detroit-Fire Dept. (Box 15)
    - Detroit Tunnel (Box 15)
    - Erie RR (Box 15)
    - Features (interesting quotes or information about JFJ) (Box 15)
    - Forbes, John M. (Box 15)
    - Great Western RR (Box 15)
    - Hannibal & St. Joseph RR (Box 15)
    - Historical
      - Bridges (Box 15)
      - Cairo, Ill. (Box 15)
      - Chicago, Ill. (Box 15)
      - Detroit (Box 15)
      - Illinois (Box 15)
      - Iowa (Box 15)
      - Kansas (Box 15)
      - Land grants (Box 15)
      - Michigan (Box 15)
      - Ontonogan Rock (Box 15)
      - Railroads (Box 15)
    - Illinois Central RR (Box 15)
    - Illustrations (Box 15)
    - Jackson, Mich. (Box 15)
    - Johnston vs. Jones & Marsh (Box 15)
    - Joliet & Northern Indiana RR, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Joy and Porter (law firm) 1838-1861, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Kansas City (Box 15)
    - Kansas City & Cameron RR (Box 15)
    - Kansas City, Galveston & Lake Superior (Box 15)
    - Kansas City, St. Joseph & Council Bluffs (Box 15)
    - Kansas Land Co. (Box 15)
    - Kansas Pacific (Box 15)
    - Kansas Roads-Atchison & Nebraska RR (Box 15)
    - Keokuk & St. Paul RR (Box 15)
    - Land Grants (Box 15)
    - Lane, Ebenezer (Box 15)
    - Leavenworth, Lawrence & Galveston RR (Box 16)
    - Legal
      - 1836-1889, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Johnstone vs. Jones 1860 (Box 16)
      - Larned (Edward L.) (Box 16)
      - Railroad laws (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - Louisville, New Albany & Chicago RR (Box 16)
    - Maps of railroad lines, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Masters, Edgar Lee (Box 16)
    - Michigan Central Railroad, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Michigan Southern RR, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Missouri Pacific (Box 16)
    - Missouri River, Fort Scott & Gulf RR (Box 16)
    - Neutral lands 1867-1878, 11 folders (Box 16)
    - New Albany & Salem RR (Box 16)
    - Newspapers (Box 16)
    - Oakland and Ottawa RR (Box 16)
    - Pacific RR (Box 16)
    - Panics 1857 (Box 16)
    - Patriots War 1837-1838 (Box 16)
    - Pere Marquette RR (Box 16)
    - Prohibition (Box 16)
    - Publicity, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Pullman Car Co. (Box 16)
    - Railroad passes (Box 16)
    - Rock Island RR (Box 16)
    - Soo Canal, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Statistics-railroads, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Stock yards (Box 17)
    - Thompson, Benjamin (Box 17)
    - Union Pacific, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Union stockyards-Chicago (Box 17)
    - Wabash RR (Box 17)
    - Welland Canal (Box 17)
- John W. Brooks Papers
  In 1846, Joy and an associate, John W. Brooks, purchased the Michigan Central Railroad line from the state of Michigan. At that time, the line went only from Detroit to Kalamazoo. Brooks later became a director of the Chicago, Burlington & Quincy Railroad and president and director of the Burlington and Missouri River Railroad. The John W. Brooks series consists of copied business correspondence arranged both chronologically and alphabetically.
  - Letters (arranged alphabetically)
    (negative photostats)
    - Blogett, M. (Box 17)
    - Corning, Erastus (Box 17)
    - Forbes, John Murray (Box 17)
      (also include original letter, 1852)
    - Hammond, C.G. (Box 17)
    - Joy, James F. (Box 17)
    - Lathrop, J.L. (Box 17)
    - Litchfield, E.C. (Box 17)
    - Mills, Henry (Box 17)
    - Morton, E. (Box 17)
    - Porter, George F. (Box 17)
    - Porter, J.F. (Box 17)
    - Rice, R.N. (Box 17)
    - Richmond, W.A. (Box 17)
    - Thayer, J.E. (Box 17)
    - Thayer, J.E. & Bro. (Box 17)
    - Walker, H.N. (Box 17)
    - Ward, R.E. (Box 17)
    - Williamson, D.D. (Box 17)
  - Letters by date
    - 1843-1868, negative photostats (Box 17)
    - 1843-1877, typescripts (Box 18)
  - Copies of documents (formerly in binders)
    - Photostats of originals, typescripts, and carbon of typescripts, arranged chronologically (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 19)
      (continued)
    - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 20)
- Abraham Lincoln research
  The Abraham Lincoln Research series consists of drafts of writings on the life of Abraham Lincoln, copies of research done in newspapers about Lincoln, and information about significant Lincoln events.
  - Drafts of writings about Lincoln (unprocessed) (Box 21)
  - Drafts of writings about Lincoln (unprocessed) (Box 22)
  - Drafts of writings about Lincoln (unprocessed) (Box 23)
  - Newspaper research (photostatic copies and typescripts) (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous (unprocessed) (Box 25)
- Office Correspondence
  The Office Correspondence series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and consists of exchanges between Gilchrist and those individuals and repositories that were helpful to him in the accumulation by his office of documentation on James F. Joy and Abraham Lincoln.
  - A (Box 26)
  - Alcock, John (Box 26)
  - Angle, Paul (Box 26)
  - Ayres, Frank C. (Box 26)
  - Baldwin, W. W. (Box 26)
  - Blair, G. (Box 26)
  - Bogart, Ernest (Box 26)
  - Bowers, Claude G. (Box 26)
  - Briggs, Morris H. (Box 26)
  - Brooks, Henry G. (Box 26)
  - Corliss, C. J. (Box 26)
  - D (Box 26)
  - Dartmouth College (Box 26)
  - Dennison Voice Writing System (Box 26)
  - E (Box 26)
  - F (Box 26)
  - Farnum, Henry W. (Box 26)
  - Frost, Norman B. (Box 26)
  - G (Box 26)
  - Gilchrist, Stephen I. (Box 26)
  - Greenslet, Ferris (Box 26)
  - H (Box 26)
  - Hale, Richard W. (Box 26)
  - Harlan, Edgar R. (Box 26)
  - Harvard University (Box 26)
  - Hay, J.O. (Box 26)
  - Hay, Logan (Box 26)
  - Henderson, Victor (Box 26)
  - Herriot, F.I. (Box 26)
  - I (Box 26)
  - J (Box 26)
  - Johnson, Allan (Box 26)
  - Joy, Helen N. (Box 27)
  - Joy, Henry B., 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Joy, James R. (Box 27)
  - K (Box 27)
  - Kidd, John G. (Box 27)
  - L (Box 27)
  - M (Box 27)
  - Mc (Box 27)
  - McClellan, George B. (Box 27)
  - McConkey, M.C. (Box 27)
  - Meserve, Frederick H. (Box 27)
  - Mines, L.F. (Box 27)
  - Murphy, Maurice (Box 27)
  - N (Box 27)
  - O (Box 27)
  - P (Box 27)
  - Payne, Charles E. (Box 27)
  - Q (Box 27)
  - R (Box 27)
  - Redding, Leo L. (Box 27)
  - Sampson, Lewis D. (Box 27)
  - Scaife, Roger L. (Box 27)
  - Shaw, W.W. (Box 27)
  - Skeels, Chipman (Box 27)
  - Smith, William E. (Box 27)
  - Sturgis, Charles I. (Box 27)
  - Sullivan, E.W. (Box 27)
  - T (Box 27)
  - Tyler, Lyon G. (Box 27)
  - U (Box 27)
  - V (Box 27)
  - W (Box 27)
  - Winthrop, Beekman (Box 27)
  - Woodward, W.E. (Box 27)
  - Wright, Elias A. (Box 27)
  - XYZ (Box 27)